[

](https://corporate.britannica.com/)

Menu

Encyclopaedia Britannica, Inc.  
Privacy Policy

Last Updated and Effective as of: February 8, 2024\*  
_\*_This Site is affiliated with CMI Marketing, Inc., d/b/a Raptive (“**Raptive**“) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site, and Raptive will collect and use certain data for advertising purposes. To learn more about Raptive’s data usage, click here_: [Raptive’s Advertising Privacy Statement](https://cafemedia.com/publisher-advertising-privacy-policy/)._

Your use of our Services is governed by our [Terms of Use](https://corporate.britannica.com/termsofuse.html)_.  **O**_UR [TERMS OF USE](http://corporate.britannica.com/termsofuse.html) CONTAIN DISCLAIMERS OF WARRANTIES AND LIABILITY, GOVERNING LAW AND VENUE, AND CLASS ACTION WAIVER PROVISIONS. THESE PROVISIONS AFFECT YOUR RIGHTS ABOUT HOW TO RESOLVE ANY DISPUTE WITH ENCYCLOPAEDIA BRITANNICA, INCLUDING UNDER THIS PRIVACY NOTICE. PLEASE REVIEW. YOUR USE OF THE SERVICES IS ACCEPTANCE OF THIS PRIVACY NOTICE AND OUR [TERMS OF USE](http://corporate.britannica.com/termsofuse.html).

Please note:

* The [Britannica Kids & Student Data](https://corporate.britannica.com/privacy-policy?elementor-preview=3&ver=1707399566#student-data) section of this Privacy Notice applies to our Britannica Kids’ Service, which is our ad-free, premium subscription service that is intended for use by kids in grades pre-K-12 (our “Kids’ Service”).  

* Our [Britannica Education Privacy Policy](https://corporate.britannica.com/privacy.html) located at [https://corporate.britannica.com/privacy.html,](https://corporate.britannica.com/privacy.html) not this Privacy Notice, applies to data processed in connection with an institution’s and its users’ subscription-based use of our Britannica Education suite of instructional, research and training solutions (our “Institutional Services”).  

* Games are not included in the ad-free experience offered in connection with the purchase of a subscription to one of our [Premium](https://premium.britannica.com/) services.  

Table of Contents 
==================

[Purposes of Processing the Information that You Provide to Us](#purpose-of-processing)  
[Correcting, Updating, or Removing Personal Information; Account Deletion](#Correcting-Updating)  

**Introduction**
================

Your privacy is important to us.  We understand that you are aware of and care about your own personal privacy interests, and we take that seriously. This Privacy Notice sets forth your privacy rights and applies to personal information we may collect: through our websites, mobile applications or online services that link to this Privacy Notice (our “Services”); how we will use, disclose and protect this information; and how you can opt out of some of our uses and disclosures of your information. This Privacy Notice does not apply to information collected by our authorized, third-party service providers or that we collect in other ways, such as over the phone, by mail or in person, except where stated otherwise or as required by law.

Your decision to use any of our Services and provide your personal information is voluntary. We indicate on our online, mobile, and other registration forms what types of personal information are requested. You may choose not to submit requested information online, or may choose to restrict the use of cookies (see our [Cookie Policy](https://corporate.britannica.com/cookie_policy.html) and ‘[Your Rights & Choices; Opt-Out](#opt-out)‘ below for more information), but that may limit the services we are able to provide to you.

Except for our Kids’ Service and our Institutional Services, the Services are a network of general audience sites, and are not targeted to, and do not knowingly collect personal information from, minors under 16 years of age. We request that these individuals do not provide personal information through the Services. Please see ‘[COPPA Compliance](#coppa-compliance)‘ below for more information.

We recognize that information privacy is an ongoing responsibility, and so we will from time to time update this Privacy Notice as we undertake new personal information collection practices or adopt new privacy policies. If you have concerns, please contact our data protection officer at [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). This Privacy Notice replaces our former privacy policy dated June 1, 2023. You can request a copy of our former privacy policy by sending an email to [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

**COPPA Compliance**
====================

In accordance with the Federal Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we will never knowingly solicit, nor will we accept, personal information from users known to be under thirteen (13) years of age without the consent of their educational institution or the child’s parent or guardian. We do, however, use COPPA-compliant, third-party services that automatically collect or share certain information and usage data with us to support our internal operations as described in this Privacy Notice.

If an educational institution with students that are under thirteen (13) years of age uses our Institutional Services, the educational institution also may provide us with personal information about its students. We use student information to provide the subscribed-to Institutional Service to the educational institution and its students as provided in the [Britannica Education Privacy Policy](https://corporate.britannica.com/privacy.html).

If you believe that we have collected personal information from someone under the age of 13, please contact us at: [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)[\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)[\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

**Information that You Provide to Us**
======================================

Britannica protects the identity of visitors to the Services by limiting the collection of personal information. Except with your consent, personal information provided by you to us will not be posted or published by us, and will be shared with our authorized, third-party vendors or service providers.  You can enjoy many of our Services and their special features without giving us your personal information. See also [How We Use Information that You Provide to Us](#how-we-use).

**Use of Our Premium Subscription Services**

When you subscribe to one of our ad-free (Games not included), premium Services, we collect information about you (in accordance with applicable privacy laws) that may include (but not be limited to) your email address, first and name, title, IP address, device ID and shared favorites.  We may also collect a personal mailing address and phone number. You may edit your information at any time to change, add or remove certain personal information by visiting your [Britannica Account Settings](http://myaccount.britannica.com/) page or sending an email to [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). We process your personal information to administer and manage your subscription, deliver the subscriber benefits described below, inform you of prizes and other benefits or opportunities associated with your subscription and respond to your information requests. We may also use this information for legitimate business purposes that help us analyze the demographic of our subscribers and understand our users’ needs and interests to better tailor our products and services to meet user needs and deliver additional services to our users. 

**Promotions and other special features**

For certain promotions and to access certain features available throughout our Services, including our free, ad-supported Services, we collect information voluntarily submitted by you to us to deliver the requested feature that may include (but not be limited to) your email address, first and last name, title, IP address and device ID. We may also collect a personal mailing address and phone number.  You may edit this information at any time to change, add or remove it from our Services by visiting your [Britannica Account Settings](http://myaccount.britannica.com/) page or sending an email to [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).  We process your personal information to deliver the requested feature to you, inform you of other benefits or opportunities associated with our Services, including the benefits described below. We may also use this information for legitimate business purposes that help us understand our users’ needs and interests to better tailor our products and services to meet your needs.

**Newsletters**

You may wish to register for or subscribe to a Britannica newsletter without becoming a Britannica subscriber. To receive these newsletters by email, you must provide us with your email address.  We use [Autopilot by Ortto](https://ortto.com/privacy/) and [Salesforce](https://www.salesforce.com/company/privacy/), our third-party service providers, to deliver our newsletters to you. When you open an email that contains a newsletter, we gather certain statistics, such as number of emails opened and clicks within a newsletter, using industry-standard technologies, including clear gifs, helping us monitor and improve our newsletters. For more information, please see [Autopilot’s Privacy Policy](https://ortto.com/privacy/) and [Salesforce’s Privacy Statement](https://www.salesforce.com/company/privacy/). Except for Autopilot and Salesforce, we do not share your voluntarily provided email address with any third party.   

You may manage your Britannica newsletter and email preferences by subscribing or unsubscribing at any time using the link included in the related newsletter or marketing email or visiting the ‘Notifications and Emails’ section of your [Britannica Account Settings](http://myaccount.britannica.com/) page. Please note that if you have set your browser to block cookies, this may have an impact on your ability to unsubscribe. If you have any difficulties managing your email or other communication preferences with Britannica, please contact [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

**Games & Quizzes**

Whenever you play our Games & Quizzes, we collect data about your interactions with each Game or Quiz. This information may be associated with your username, IP address or device ID for the purpose of providing our Services and improving them. In addition, when you play a Game or Quiz, your username, related photo and score may be displayed in our “Leaderboard” for other players to see. If you do not want your username and related photo displayed in the Leaderboard, please refrain from playing our Games or Quizzes.

**Logging in using social networking credentials**

If you log-in to our Services using a social media (such as Facebook or Twitter) log-in, you are granting permission to the social media service to share your user details with us. This may include your name, email address, date of birth and location, which will then be used to create a Britannica identity. These social media services may use information about your visit to our Services on their pages. If you browse these pages while still logged in to your account with us, information they collect may be connected to your account on their Web site. For more information on how these social media services use information, please review their privacy policies.

**Posting from home**

You should be aware that if you or your friends post the location of your home and that information is published on a Service it may be available to others and may be published by third parties without our control. To request removal of location data please email us at [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

**Prospect and Referral Information**

If a User visits a Service and submits an email address to Britannica but fails to complete the registration or purchase process, we may use such “prospect” information to contact the prospective User from time to time with offers from Britannica or its wholly owned subsidiary, Merriam-Webster, Incorporated (“Merriam-Webster”) and information about new features, new services, and special discounts we think the User may see as valuable. Similarly, if a User forwards a Britannica email to a friend, we may use the “referral” information provided to contact the friend from time to time with offers from Britannica or Merriam-Webster and information about new features, new services, and special discounts we think the friend may see as valuable. We do not sell or rent any contact information for such “prospects” or “referrals.”

**Payment card information**

You may choose to purchase goods or subscription services from Britannica using a payment card. Typically, payment card information is provided directly by you via the Services, into the PCI/DSS-compliant payment processing service to which Britannica subscribes, and Britannica does not, itself, process or store your card information.

**How We Use Information that You Provide to Us**
=================================================

**Subscriber Communications**

As a benefit of membership, Britannica subscribers may receive the following communications from us or our wholly owned subsidiary, Merriam-Webster:

* **Communications related to subscription maintenance activities.** These communications may include, without limitation, notices regarding material changes to Britannica Service policies, service updates, service enhancements, and account management procedures. Since these communications are necessary to ensure Britannica provides its subscribers with the highest quality of services, our subscribers are not permitted to opt out from receipt of these communications.
* **Newsletter Communications.** As a benefit of a Britannica subscription, we may send Britannica subscribers our exclusive Britannica or Merriam-Webster newsletters. To unsubscribe to a newsletter, a User can either (i) follow the instructions at the bottom of any newsletter or (ii) visit the ‘Notifications and Emails’ section of their [Britannica Account Settings](http://myaccount.britannica.com/) page.
* **Communications containing information about Britannica or Merriam-Webster products and services.**
* We may send promotional emails and other outbound communications to Britannica subscribers regarding products and services from Britannica or Merriam-Webster. Any Britannica subscriber that does not wish to receive such product and service communications can choose to remove their contact information from our contact list at any time by (i) following the instructions at the bottom of any promotional email; (ii) visiting the ‘Notifications and Emails’ section of their [Britannica Account Settings](http://myaccount.britannica.com/) page; or (iii) sending an email to [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).  

**Non-subscriber communications from us and our approved, third-party partners**

If you choose to provide us with personal information on any of our free, ad-supported Services, you may receive the following types of emails from us:

* Emails related to subscription-maintenance activities;
* Emails highlighting new features, content, and usage tips for the Services; and
* Special offers
    * From us for additional Britannica or Merriam-Webster products and services, and
    * From our approved, third-party partners, if you “opt-in” or give us your permission to send them.

When you provide us with your personal information, you can let us know that you do not wish to receive special offers from Britannica, Merriam-Webster or Britannica’s third-party partners. Also, each special offer will have information available to allow you to “opt-out” if you no longer wish to receive special offers.

**Authorized service providers**

For legitimate business interests, we may share your personal information with service providers that perform certain services on our behalf, such as processing credit card payments, performing business and sales analysis, and supporting our Services’ functionality, including Autopilot and Salesforce.

**Business partners**

When you make purchases or engage in our promotions, we may share personal information with the businesses with which we partner to offer you those products, services, promotions, contests and/or sweepstakes. When you elect to engage in a particular merchant’s offer or program, you expressly authorize us to provide your email address and other information to that merchant.

**Surveys**

We may occasionally conduct on-line surveys. All surveys are voluntary and you may decline to participate.

**Direct mail partners**

From time to time we may share our postal mailing list with selected providers of goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you prefer not to receive mailings from these providers, you can notify us at any time by sending an email to [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

**Law enforcement**

We also may disclose your information: In response to a subpoena or as otherwise required by law. When we believe disclosure is appropriate in connection with efforts to investigate, prevent, or take other action regarding illegal activity, suspected fraud or other wrongdoing; to protect and defend the rights, property or safety of Britannica, our Users, our employees, or others; to comply with applicable law or cooperate with law enforcement; or to enforce our [Terms of Use](https://corporate.britannica.com/termsofuse.html) or other agreements or policies.=

**Purposes of Processing the Information That You Provide to Us**
=================================================================

As explained above, Britannica processes your data to provide you with the products and services you have requested or purchased from us, including subscriptions, special features, newsletters and other content.  Sometimes we use third-party providers to facilitate the delivery of the services described above, and these third-party providers may be supplied with or have access to your personal information for the sole purpose of providing services to you on our behalf, such as our newsletters.

We also use your data for legitimate business purposes that enable us to refine our products and services to better tailor them to your needs and communicate with you about other products and services offered by Britannica.  In addition, we may disclose your personal information in special legal circumstances. For instance, such information may be used where it is necessary to protect our copyright or intellectual property rights, or if the law requires us to do so.

You can update your personal information and change your marketing preferences at any time by visiting your [Britannica Account Settings](http://myaccount.britannica.com/) page or sending an email to [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

**Links to Other Websites**
===========================

This Privacy Notice only governs information collected by Britannica through your use of the Services.  Our Services contain links to websites or content (including advertisements on our free, ad-supported Services and Games) operated and maintained by third parties over which we have no control, including [Raptive](https://www.cafemedia.com/publisher-advertising-privacy-policy) for the purposes of placing advertising on the pages in the Services, including Games.  We encourage you to review the privacy policies of all third-party websites before disclosing any personal information to the website. Do not supply personal information to third-party websites unless you have verified their security and privacy policies.

**Information Collected Automatically**
=======================================

Like other commercial websites, Britannica and our authorized, third-party service providers use cookies (small files transferred from a website to its visitors’ hard drives or browsers for record-keeping purposes), including Strictly Necessary, Performance, Functional and Personalization cookies, and other similar information-gathering technologies throughout our Services to collect certain information automatically and store it in log files for a variety of legitimate business interests and purposes. This information may include (but is not limited to) internet protocol (IP) addresses, mobile device identifiers, the region or general location from where your computer or device is accessing the internet, browser type, operating system and other usage information about your use of our Services, including a history of the pages you view. Please refer to our [Cookie Policy](https://corporate.britannica.com/cookie_policy.html), as well as [Raptive’s Advertising Privacy Statement](https://cafemedia.com/publisher-advertising-privacy-policy/) for more information.

Web beacons, tags, and scripts also may be used on our Services or in email or other electronic communications we send to you. These assist us in delivering cookies, counting visits to our Services, understanding usage and campaign effectiveness and determining whether an email has been opened and acted upon. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by our third-party service providers on an individual and aggregated basis.

Britannica and its authorized, third-party service providers use cookies, beacons, and other similar technologies on our Services either with your consent or for our legitimate business purposes to ensure you can navigate or otherwise use our Services and access secure areas of our Services.  We also use these technologies for statistical purposes and to analyze and improve the use of our Services and prepare aggregated usage reports.

As described below, on our free, ad-supported Services and Games, we use these technologies for our legitimate business purposes of providing standard advertising controls, determining user response to advertisements and promotions, and delivering targeted advertisements that we or our authorized, third-party service providers believe will be of most interest to you.

We may also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our servers and to administer our Services, analyze trends, track visitor movements, and gather broad demographic information that assists us in identifying visitor preferences.

We have a legitimate interest in understanding how our users, subscribers, customers, and potential customers use our Services. Among other things, this assists us in providing more relevant products and services.  Please refer to our [Cookie Policy](https://corporate.britannica.com/cookie_policy.html) and ‘[Your Rights & Choices; Opt-Out](#opt-out)‘ below for more information.

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Services. For more information about cookies, please visit [All About Cookies.](https://allaboutcookies.org/)

* **Analytics & usage data  
      
    **

_For our legitimate business interests, we may process your personal information for analytic purposes on all of our Services as described in this section._ 

Together with [Google Analytics](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en), we use cookies and software logs to monitor the use of the Services and to gather non-personal information about visitors to the site. These monitoring systems allow us to track general information about our visitors, such as the type of browsers (for example, Firefox or Internet Explorer), the operating systems (for instance, Windows or Macintosh), or the Internet providers (for instance, Comcast) they use. This information is used for statistical and market research purposes to tailor content to usage patterns and to provide services requested by our customers.

We also have implemented certain [Google Analytics Advertiser](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads) features. These tools use cookies to collect and store standard Internet log and visitor information on our behalf, including information about what pages you visit, how long you are on our sites, how you got here, and what you click on during your visit. This Google Analytics data is not tied to personal information, so this information cannot be used to identify who you are. We use the data provided by Google Analytics to develop our services and content around our User demographics, interests, and behavior on our Services. You can opt-out of this Google Analytics Advertiser feature using the Ads Settings located at [https://www.google.com/settings/ads](https://www.google.com/settings/ads). In addition, you can use the [Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) to disable tracking by Google Analytics.  To delete these cookies, please see your browser’s privacy settings or follow the above instructions.

We may also receive other data about your use of our Services from other sources.  This information may include (but is not limited to) information about your activities across unrelated websites and mobile applications, information about the possible relationships between different browsers and devices and information that we receive from our third-party service providers. We may add this information to the information to the information we have already collect through our Services.

* ****Advertising on our free, ad-supported Services and Games  
      
    ****

Our free (non-subscription) Services and Games are supported by advertising and affiliated with [Raptive](https://cafemedia.com/publisher-advertising-privacy-policy/) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Services and Games. [Raptive](https://cafemedia.com/publisher-advertising-privacy-policy/) will collect and use certain data for advertising purposes. To learn more about Raptive’s data usage and your related rights, please click here: [Raptive’s Advertising Privacy Statement](https://cafemedia.com/publisher-advertising-privacy-policy/). [Raptive’s](https://cafemedia.com/publisher-advertising-privacy-policy/) Consent Management Platform (CMP) is LiveRamp with the CMP identification number 3. 

We also may work with DigiTrust to set a cookie in your browser to enable us and [DigiTrust Partners](http://www.digitru.st/participating-companies/) to collect web viewing data that includes visits to a Britannica Service and other non-affiliated websites over time. This data may be used to infer whether you share interests with other Users and deliver advertising relevant to those inferences. You can exercise choice about the collection of data in this way for interest-based, behavioral advertising by visiting the [Digital Advertising Alliance’s choice page](http://optout.aboutads.info/#!/) and opting out from DigiTrust or use one of the links provided [below](#opt-out). Opting out from DigiTrust will stop DigiTrust Partners from using the DigiTrust identifier. Through the DAA choice page, you may make other choices for companies that participate in the DAA, some of which are DigiTrust Partners.

Our ad-supported Services and Games may also rely on third-party service providers to do things like: take user-level information, anonymize it through hashing (a hashed email address might look something like this: **e820bb4aba5ad74c5a6ff1aca16641f6**) and match it against other anonymized, people-based identifiers – doing this helps us serve you personalized, relevant advertisements.  Specifically, when you use our ad-supported Services, we may share information that we may collect from you, including your email (in hashed form), IP address or information about your browser or operating system, with our third-party service providers, Index Exchange (IX) and LiveRamp Inc. and its group companies (‘LiveRamp’). IX and LiveRamp may use our first party cookie on your browser to match your shared information to their marketing databases in order to provide back a pseudonymous privacy-centric identifier for our use in real time bidding in digital advertising. These third parties may in turn link further demographic or interest-based information to your browser. You have the choice to opt-out of the use of your data by third-party service providers for this purpose at any time.  Please find more information about opting out [below](#opt-out).

Please note that limiting third-party cookies via your browser controls does not prevent our first-party cookies from being set in this way. Also, please know, if you opt-out of interest-based advertising you will continue to receive ads on our free, ad-supported Services and Games, but not behaviorally targeted ads. Also, if you opt-out of Britannica’s practices, you may continue to receive interest-based advertising through other companies.  If you erase your browser’s cookies, you may need to perform this process again.

* **Anonymous** **data  
      
    **

Anonymous aggregated data may be provided to other companies we do business with for statistical purposes. For example, we may report to advertisers that a certain percentage of our site’s visitors are adults between the ages of 25 and 35.

* **Device identifiers  
      
    **

_For our legitimate business interests, we process your device identifiers as described in this section._ 

 When you use a mobile device like a tablet or cell phone to access our Services, we may access and monitor one or more “device identifiers.” Device identifiers are small data files associated with your mobile device that uniquely identify your mobile device. A device identifier may deliver information to us or a third party partner about how you browse and use the services and may help us or others provide reports or personalized ads. Some features of the services may not function properly if use or availability of device identifiers is impaired or disabled.

**Third-party activities**

_For our legitimate business interests, and with your consent where this is required, we may process data collected by us for advertising, including interest-based advertising, as described in this section._

As described above, in order to monetize our free, ad-supported Services and Games, we work with third-party service providers, advertisers and advertising networks that use cookies and other similar technologies to target ads served to our free, ad-supported Services. Our Privacy Notice does not cover the use of data that you provide directly to advertisers or third-party partners; that usage is governed by the advertiser’s or third party partner’s privacy policy.

What does it mean to “serve ads”? When you visit a website, your Internet browser transmits a “request” to the computer that hosts the website (the “host server”) requesting that server to send you (or “serve”) the Web page that you are seeking. Most Web pages contain components that are pulled from different sources, for example, a Web page at a news site may get its weather section from one provider, its sports results from a different source, and advertisements from other servers. Our Web pages contain coding that directs your browser to fill the ad spaces on the Web pages with content served by advertisers and advertising networks to whom we have sold the ad spaces. These advertisers and advertising networks use cookies and beacons to help manage ad delivery and frequency and to identify audience segment(s) for customized advertising (“targeting”). These cookies are used to identify your IP address, so that when you visit another website using the same advertising network, the advertising network will recognize the cookie as one of its own, read the information on the cookie (the record of which sites in the network you have visited) and serve you an ad that you might be interested in, based on your past visits to other sites in the network. Advertising targeted based on past Web surfing is known as “behavioral advertising.”

Britannica does not provide any personal information to third-party service providers, such as Raptive, advertisers or advertising networks about visitors to the Services. Our Privacy Notice does not cover the use of information that may have been collected from you by third parties on other websites. If you would like to learn more about behavioral advertising or to opt-out of having this information used by companies that are part of the Network Advertising Initiative to deliver targeted ads, please visit [http://www.networkadvertising.org](http://www.networkadvertising.org/). Many of the same companies are members of the Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising. You can learn more and opt-out of receiving targeted ads from them at [http://www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices).

Some advertising networks require that we specifically list their opt-out links below. When you opt-out of a network, you may receive a “opt-out” cookie so that the network will know not to assign you new cookies in the future. You will continue to receive ads from that network, but not behaviorally targeted ads. If you erase your browser’s cookies, you may need to perform this process again.

* Exponential Interactive, Inc. has a legitimate interest to collect and profile personal data in the form of IP address and cookie ID from users on our website in order to provide targeted online advertising and ad measurement. For more details including opt-out requests, access requests, or complaints, please review their [privacy policy](http://exponential.com/privacy/) or contact their data protection officer via [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

**Your Rights & Choices; Opt-Out Choices**
==========================================

[Raptive’s Advertising Privacy Statement](https://cafemedia.com/publisher-advertising-privacy-policy/) more fully describes the cookies, beacons and other similar technology used on our Services for advertising purposes and provides information on when and how users can accept or reject them. 

You can opt-out of being behaviorally targeted by Britannica (and other companies employing online advertising) via the following options:

**Please remember, if you opt-out of interest-based advertising you will continue to receive ads on our free, ad-supported Services and Games, but not behaviorally targeted ads. Also, if you opt-out of Britannica’s practices, you may continue to receive interest-based advertising through other companies.**

**Browser controls**

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Services. For more information about cookies, please visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org/](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). Please note that limiting third-party cookies via your browser controls does not prevent our first-party cookies from being set in this way.

* To manage or delete browser cookies, please see your browser’s privacy settings.
* To manage or delete Flash cookies, please use the Adobe Flash Player Settings Manager here: [http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings\_manager07.html](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html)

**Google Analytics**

You can control the use of your personal data by Google Analytics by visiting the ‘Your privacy controls’ section of the Google Privacy Policy located at [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-US#infochoices](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en-US#infochoices). You also can use the Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-on to disable tracking by Google Analytics.  To delete these cookies, please see your browser’s privacy settings or follow the above instructions.

**IX & LiveRamp**

You can control the use of your personal data by IX and LiveRamp as follows:

IX’s options for users to opt-out of personalized advertising can be found on the IX website at this link: [https://www.indexexchange.com/privacy/](https://www.indexexchange.com/privacy/).  IX may continue to add opt-out options. 

To opt out of LiveRamp’s use of your personal data, please head here: [https://liveramp.com/opt\_out/](https://liveramp.com/opt_out/).

**How we respond to “Do Not Track” signals**

When you visit a website in any browser, you automatically share information with that website, such as your IP address, and other standard PC information. If the website contains content provided by a third-party website (for example a web measurement tools such as a web beacon or scripts), some information about you may be automatically sent to the content provider.  This type of arrangement has several benefits, such as allowing you to access third-party content from our Services conveniently. Some internet browsers or other tools include “Do Not Track” (DNT) features that, when turned on, send a signal to websites you visit indicating you do not wish to be tracked across websites over time. However, since no technological standard for DNT signals has been developed or adopted to date, our Services do not currently respond to DNT signals.

**Britannica Kids & Student Data**
==================================

**A note to minors:** If you are under the age of 16, please get permission from your parent/legal guardian or school before using the Services. If we discover that we have collected any personally identifiable information from a child under the age of 16 without the proper consents required by law, we will suspend the associated account and/or remove that information from our database as soon as possible.

Britannica does not knowingly collect or solicit personally identifiable information from or about children under 16, except as permitted by law or otherwise provided herein. If we discover we have received any information from a child under 16 in violation of this policy, we will delete that information immediately. If you believe Britannica has any information from or about anyone under 16, please email us at [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

**Student Data**

Our [Britannica Education Privacy Policy](https://corporate.britannica.com/privacy.html) located at [https://corporate.britannica.com/privacy.html,](https://corporate.britannica.com/privacy.html) not this Privacy Notice, applies to data processed in connection with an institution’s and its users’ subscription-based use of our Institutional Services.

In general, if you are a student with access to our Institutional Services through an Institutional Subscription License Agreement between your school institution and us, your student service data is processed in a way that is COPPA- and FERPA-compliant.  As you use the Institutional Services, you may enter student data or interact with student data that has already been entered. Under the terms of our contracts with school institutions, we agree to act as a “School Official” as defined by the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), meaning that we:

* Perform an institutional service or function for which the school or district would otherwise use its own employees;
* Have been determined to meet the criteria set forth in the school’s or district’s annual notification of FERPA rights for being a School Official with a legitimate educational interest in the education records;
* Are under the direct control of the school or district with regard to the use and maintenance of education records; and
* Use education records only for authorized purposes and will not re-disclose from education records to other parties (unless we have specific authorization from the school or district to do so and it is otherwise permitted by FERPA).  

However, FERPA requires limitations on disclosure of those records and implementation of appropriate security measures to protect those records. To help your school district comply with FERPA, we have adopted certain practices, and require that educators using this site fulfill certain responsibilities to safeguard student data.

The following statement explains our practices and your responsibilities regarding the student data you enter on this site.

**Student Data Security & Confidentiality Statement**

**Purposes of Data Entry**

You control what student data is entered on our Kids’ Service or Institutional Services and you always retain ownership of the student data. Student data entered on this site should be limited to information that is relevant to the legitimate educational purpose of improving student performance. We will not ask you to enter, and you are instructed not to enter, data about students that is not relevant to this legitimate educational purpose.

Therefore, only a minimum amount of personally identifiable student data required for the setup of the system is requested. Additional data, not specific to the student, is also required to complete system setup, including the teacher first and last name, class name, grade level, and school name.

**Use, Disclosure, and Storage**

We will use the student data to provide the subscribed-to Institutional Services to your school institution. We will not keep the student data after you or the school district instructs us to delete it.

We will only disclose student data to authorized employees or representatives of the school institution and will not knowingly disclose the student data to any third person without express written authorization. When, at the request of the school institution, we acquire assessment or other information, including personally identifiable student data, from a third-party source we treat that information with the same confidentiality and security safeguards as though it were provided directly by the school institution. Additional agreements may be required by the third party to authorize transmission of data to us.

Your school institution may from time to time request that we provide student data to third parties of its choosing. We will do so with written authorization, which acknowledges that we are providing that data as the requesting institution’s agent and that once the data is received by the third party, we no longer have any control over the use or disposition of the data.

We may also use aggregated data in our research, product development, and marketing. That aggregated, non-personally identifiable data (e.g., summary or statistical data) may be shared with third parties. However, we do not use personally identifiable student data to market any products or services directly to students or their parents.

If we wish, from time to time, to release aggregated data that identifies a school or school district by name, we will enter into a separate agreement with the institution to authorize release and publication.

We do not utilize third parties to provide products and do not share your student data with any third parties.

**Security** **of Your Information**
====================================

Britannica is committed to keeping your personal information safe and secure. Any personal information collected through the Services is stored on limited-access servers. We maintain a comprehensive information security program and seek to use commercially reasonable organizational, physical, technical and administrative safeguards to protect these servers and the information they store from unauthorized access, use, disclosure, loss or modification. Our security measures include (among others): encryption of data; security controls that protect the entirety of Britannica’s IT infrastructure from external attack and unauthorized access; and internal policies setting out our data security approach and training for employees, including a Data Breach Notification Policy. We update and test our security technology on an ongoing basis. We strive to restrict access to your personal information to those employees who need to know that information to provide benefits or services to you. In addition, we strive to ensure that all our employees are aware of the importance of confidentiality and maintaining the privacy and security of your information.

If there is an unauthorized disclosure of personal information in Britannica’s possession or control, we will take steps in accordance with our written Incident Response Policy to investigate and mitigate the impact of the breach and notify affected customers in the manner required by applicable laws.

**Data Storage and Retention**
==============================

Your personal information is stored by us using Amazon Web Services (AWS) cloud storage solutions in the AWS Cloud – U.S. East (N. Virginia) Region, with backups in the AWS Cloud – Asia Pacific (Singapore) Region and Brazil (Sao Paulo) Region. We retain your information for the duration of your business relationship with us and as long as necessary to permit us to use it for the legitimate business purposes that we have communicated to you and comply with applicable law or regulations. For more information on where and how long your personal information is stored, and for more information on your rights of erasure and portability, please contact the Britannica’s data protection officer at [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

**Consent to Processing and Transfer of Information about You** 
================================================================

Encyclopaedia Britannica’s headquarters are in the United States. Information we collect from you will be processed in the United States and may be stored, transferred to, and processed in any country where we have facilities or in which we engage service providers.  These countries may be outside your country of residence, including the United States, and may have different data protection laws than your country.

If you are located in the European Economic Area (EEA), Encyclopaedia Britannica collects and transfers personal data out of the EEA only: with your consent; to perform a contract with you; or to fulfill a compelling legitimate interest of Encyclopaedia Britannica in a manner that does not outweigh your rights and freedoms. Encyclopaedia Britannica endeavors to apply suitable safeguards to protect the privacy and security of your personal data and to use it only consistent with your relationship with us and the practices described in this Privacy Notice.

**Correcting, Updating, or Removing Personal Information; Account Deletion**
============================================================================

Users may opt out of certain Services or correct, update, or remove certain personal information that Britannica has collected about them through any of the means listed below. Please be sure to include the following information in your correspondence:

Your email address  
Your first and last name  
Your mailing address (street, city, state, zip code, and country)  
The name of the Britannica Service to which the request applies

**Email us at:**

[\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

 **Call us at:**

(800) 323-1229 (within the United States), or  
(312) 347-7159 (outside the United States)  
Monday – Friday, 8:00 a.m. to 6:00 p.m. (U.S. Central Time).

**Write us at:** 

Britannica Customer Service, Attn: Removal from Mailing List  
325 North LaSalle Street, Suite 200  
Chicago, IL 60654-2682  
Please allow up to six (6) weeks for mailed-in or faxed opt-out requests to be processed.

**Account Deletion:**

If you no longer wish to have a registered account, you may terminate your account by sending an email to [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). Because of the way we maintain the Britannica Services, such deletion may not be immediate, and residual copies of your profile information or posts may remain on backup media for up to ninety (90) days.

**Privacy Notice for California Residents** 
============================================

This Privacy Notice for California Residents supplements the information contained elsewhere in this Privacy Notice and applies solely to all visitors, users, and others who reside in the State of California (“consumers” or “you”). We adopt this notice to comply with the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (CCPA) and any terms defined in the CCPA have the same meaning when used in this notice.

**Information We Collect**

Our websites, software applications (apps), emails (with your consent, where required by law), and other products, services and platforms collect information that identifies, relates to, describes, references, is capable of being associated with, or could reasonably be linked, directly or indirectly, with a particular consumer or device (“personal information”). In particular, our websites, apps, emails, and other products, services and platforms may have collected the following categories of personal information from its consumers within the last twelve (12) months:

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| **Category** | **Collected** |
| A.    Identifiers | YES |
| B.    Personal information categories listed in the California Customer Records statute (Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.80(e)) | YES |
| C.    Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law | NO  |
| D.    Commercial information. | YES |
| E.    Biometric information. | NO  |
| F.     Internet or other similar network activity. | YES |
| G.    Geolocation data. | YES |
| H.    Sensory data. | NO  |
| I.      Professional or employment-related information. | NO  |
| J.     Non-public education information (per the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (20 U.S.C. Section 1232g, 34 C.F.R. Part 99)). | YES |
| K.    Inferences drawn from other personal information. | YES |

Personal information does not include:

* Publicly available information from government records.
* Deidentified or aggregated consumer information.
* Information excluded from the CCPA’s scope, like:
    * health or medical information covered by the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA) and the California Confidentiality of Medical Information Act (CMIA) or clinical trial data;
    * personal information covered by certain sector-specific privacy laws, including the Fair Credit Reporting Act (FRCA), the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act (GLBA) or California Financial Information Privacy Act (FIPA), and the Driver’s Privacy.  

**Use of Personal Information**

We may use or disclose the personal information we collect for one or more of the following business purposes:

* To fulfill or meet the reason you provided the information. For example, if you share your name and contact information to request a newsletter or ask a question about our products or services, we will use that personal information to respond to your inquiry. If you provide your personal information to purchase a product or service, we or our third-party service providers will use that information to process your payment and facilitate delivery. We may also save your information to facilitate new product or service orders and requests.
* To provide, support, personalize, and develop our websites, apps, emails, and other products, services and platforms.
* To create, maintain, customize, and secure your account with us.
* To process your requests, purchases, transactions, and payments and prevent transactional fraud.
* To provide you with support and to respond to your inquiries, including investigating and addressing your concerns and monitoring and improving our responses.
* To personalize your website, apps, emails, or other product, service or platform experience and to deliver content and product and service offerings relevant to your interests, including targeted offers and ads through our websites, apps, emails, and other products, services and platforms.
* To help maintain the safety, security, and integrity of our websites, apps, emails, and other products, services and platforms, databases and other technology assets, and business.
* For testing, research, analysis, and product development, including to develop and improve our websites, apps, emails, and other products, services and platforms.
* To respond to law enforcement requests and as required by applicable law, court order, or governmental regulations.
* As described to you when collecting your personal information or as otherwise set forth in the CCPA.
* To evaluate or conduct a merger, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of some or all of the Company’s assets, whether as a going concern or as part of bankruptcy, liquidation, or similar proceeding, in which personal information held by the Company about our Website users is among the assets transferred.  

The Company will not collect additional categories of personal information or use the personal information we collected for materially different, unrelated, or incompatible purposes without providing you notice.

**Sharing Personal Information**

The Company may disclose your personal information to a third-party for a business purpose or sell your personal information, subject to your right to opt-out of those sales (see ‘_Sales of Personal Information_’ below). When we disclose personal information for a business purpose, we enter a contract that describes the purpose and requires the recipient to both keep that personal information confidential and not use it for any purpose except performing the contract. The CCPA prohibits third parties who purchase the personal information we hold from reselling it unless you have received explicit notice and an opportunity to opt-out of further sales (see ‘_Sales of Personal Information_’ below).  

We may share your personal information with the following categories of third parties:

* Subsidiaries and affiliates.
* Contractors and service providers.
* Data aggregators.
* Third parties with whom we partner to offer products and services to you.  

**Disclosures of Personal Information for a Business Purpose**

In the preceding twelve (12) months, the Company has disclosed the following categories of personal information for a business purpose:

\[Category A: Identifiers.\]  
\[Category B: California Customer Records personal information categories.\]  
\[Category F: Internet or other similar network activity.\]  
\[Category G: Geolocation Data.\]  
\[Category K: Inferences drawn from other personal information.\]

**Sales of Personal Information**

Except with respect to our Institutional Services, in the preceding twelve (12) months, the Company has sold the following categories of personal information collected through our ad-supported Services:

\[Category A: Identifiers.\]  
\[Category F: Internet or other similar network activity.\]  
\[Category G: Geolocation Data.\]  
\[Category K: Inferences drawn from other personal information.\]

The Company and our advertising partners collect the personal information identified above (such as the cookies stored on your browser, the advertising identifier on your mobile device, or the IP address of your device) when you visit our websites, apps, and other products, services and platforms, or open our emails. We, and our partners, use this information to tailor and deliver ads to you on our websites, apps, emails, and other products, services and platforms, or to help tailor ads to you when you visit others’ sites (or use others’ apps). To tailor ads that may be more relevant to you, we and/or our partners may share the information we collect with third parties.

If you do not wish for us or our partners to sell your personal information to third parties for advertising purposes, click the **“Do Not Sell My Info”** link accessible from the pages of our websites, apps, and other products, services and platforms. Note that although we will not sell your personal information after you click that button, we will continue to share some personal information with our partners (who will function as our service providers in such instance) to help us perform advertising-related functions such as, but not limited to, measuring the effectiveness of our ads, managing how many times you may see an ad, reporting on the performance of our ads, ensuring services are working correctly and securely, providing aggregate statistics and analytics, improving when and where you may see ads and/or reducing ad fraud. If you access our websites, apps, and other products, services and platforms from other devices or browsers, visit our “**Do Not Sell My Info**” link from those devices or browsers to ensure your choice applies to the data collected when you use those devices or browsers. Additionally, although clicking the “**Do Not Sell My Info**” link will opt you out of the sale of your personal information for advertising purposes, it will not opt you out of the use of previously collected and sold personal information (except for personal information sold within 90 days prior to your exercising your right to opt out) or all interest-based advertising. If you would like more information about how to opt out of interest-based advertising in desktop and mobile browsers on a particular device, please visit [http://optout.aboutads.info/#/](http://optout.aboutads.info/#/) and [http://optout.networkadvertising.org/#](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/). You may download the AppChoices app at [http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices](http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices) to opt out in connection with mobile apps or use the platform controls on your mobile device to opt out.

**Your Rights and Choices**

The CCPA provides consumers (California residents) with specific rights regarding their personal information. This section describes your CCPA rights and explains how to exercise those rights.

**_Access to Specific Information and Data Portability Rights_**

You have the right to request that the Company disclose certain information to you about our collection and use of your personal information over the past 12 months. Once we receive and confirm your verifiable consumer request, we will disclose to you:

* The categories of personal information we collected about you.
* The categories of sources for the personal information we collected about you.
* Our business or commercial purpose for collecting or selling that personal information.
* The categories of third parties with whom we share that personal information.
* The specific pieces of personal information we collected about you (also called a data portability request).
* If we disclosed your personal information for a business purpose, we will identify the personal information categories that each category of recipient obtained.  

**Deletion Request Rights**

You have the right to request that the Company delete any of your personal information that we collected from you and retained, subject to certain exceptions. Once we receive and confirm your verifiable consumer request, we will delete (and direct our service providers to delete) your personal information from our records, unless an exception applies.

We may deny your deletion request if retaining the information is necessary for us or our service provider(s) to:

1. Complete the transaction for which we collected the personal information, provide a good or service that you requested, take actions reasonably anticipated within the context of our ongoing business relationship with you, or otherwise perform our contract with you.
2. Detect security incidents, protect against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent, or illegal activity, or prosecute those responsible for such activities.
3. Debug products to identify and repair errors that impair existing intended functionality.
4. Exercise free speech, ensure the right of another consumer to exercise their free speech rights, or exercise another right provided for by law.
5. Comply with the California Electronic Communications Privacy Act (Cal. Penal Code § 1546 et. seq.).
6. Engage in public or peer-reviewed scientific, historical, or statistical research in the public interest that adheres to all other applicable ethics and privacy laws, when the information’s deletion may likely render impossible or seriously impair the research’s achievement, if you previously provided informed consent.
7. Enable solely internal uses that are reasonably aligned with consumer expectations based on your relationship with us.
8. Comply with a legal obligation.
9. Make other internal and lawful uses of that information that are compatible with the context in which you provided it.  

**_Exercising Access, Data Portability, and Deletion Rights_**

To exercise the access, data portability, and deletion rights described above, please submit a verifiable consumer request to us by either:

* Calling us at (800) 323-1229; Monday-Friday, 8:00 a.m. to 6:00 p.m. (U.S. Central Time)
* Emailing us at [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Only you, or a person registered with the California Secretary of State that you authorize to act on your behalf, may make a verifiable consumer request related to your personal information. You may also make a verifiable consumer request on behalf of your minor child.

You may only make a verifiable consumer request for access or data portability twice within a 12-month period. The verifiable consumer request must:

* Provide sufficient information that allows us to reasonably verify you are the person about whom we collected personal information or an authorized representative.
* Describe your request with sufficient detail that allows us to properly understand, evaluate, and respond to it.  

We cannot respond to your request or provide you with personal information if we cannot verify your identity or authority to make the request and confirm the personal information relates to you.

Making a verifiable consumer request does not require you to create an account with us.

We will only use personal information provided in a verifiable consumer request to verify the requestor’s identity or authority to make the request.

**_Response Timing and Format_**

We endeavor to respond to a verifiable consumer request within forty-five (45) days of its receipt. If we require more time, we will inform you of the reason and extension period in writing in accordance with CCPA requirements.

If you have an account with us, we will deliver our written response to that account. If you do not have an account with us, we will deliver our written response by mail or electronically, at your option.

 Any disclosures we provide will only cover the 12-month period preceding the verifiable consumer request’s receipt. The response we provide will also explain the reasons we cannot comply with a request, if applicable. For data portability requests, we will select a format to provide your personal information that is readily useable and should allow you to transmit the information from one entity to another entity without hindrance.

 We do not charge a fee to process or respond to your verifiable consumer request unless it is excessive, repetitive, or manifestly unfounded. If we determine that the request warrants a fee, we will tell you why we made that decision and provide you with a cost estimate before completing your request.

**_Personal Information Sales Opt-Out and Opt-In Rights_**

If you are 16 years of age or older, you have the right to direct us to not sell your personal information at any time (the “right to opt-out”). We do not sell the personal information of consumers we actually know are less than 16 years of age, unless we receive affirmative authorization (the “right to opt-in”) from either the consumer who is between 13 and 16 years of age, or the parent or guardian of a consumer less than 13 years of age. Consumers who opt-in to personal information sales may opt-out of future sales at any time.

To exercise the right to opt-out, you (or your authorized representative) may submit a request to us by emailing [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

Once you make an opt-out request, we will wait at least twelve (12) months before asking you to reauthorize personal information sales. However, you may change your mind and opt back in to personal information sales at any time by clearing cookies from your browser or emailing [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

 You do not need to create an account with us to exercise your opt-out rights. We will only use personal information provided in an opt-out request to review and comply with the request.

**Non-Discrimination**

We will not discriminate against you for exercising any of your CCPA rights. Unless permitted by the CCPA, we will not:

* Deny you goods or services.
* Charge you different prices or rates for like-goods or services, including through granting discounts or other benefits, or imposing penalties.
* Provide you a different level or quality of like-goods or services.
* Suggest that you may receive a different price or rate for like-goods or services or a different level or quality of like-goods or services.  

However, we may offer you certain financial incentives permitted by the CCPA that can result in different prices, rates, or quality levels.  Any CCPA-permitted financial incentive we offer will reasonably relate to your Personal Information’s value and contain written terms that describe the program’s material aspects. Participation in a financial incentive program requires your prior opt in consent, which you may revoke at any time.  **We do not currently provide any financial incentives.**

**Other California Privacy Rights**

 California’s “Shine the Light” law (Civil Code Section § 1798.83) permits users of our websites, mobile applications, and other products, services and platforms that are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or write us at: Encyclopaedia Britannica, Inc., Attn: M.G. Kim, DPO, 325 N. LaSalle Street, Suite 200, Chicago, Illinois 60654.

**Changes to Our Privacy Notice**

The Company reserves the right to amend this privacy notice at our discretion and at any time. When we make changes to this privacy notice, we will post the updated notice on our website at [https://corporate.britannica.com/privacy-policy/](https://corporate.britannica.com/privacy-policy/) and update the notice’s effective date. **Your continued use of our websites, mobile applications, and other products, services and platforms** **following the posting of changes constitutes your acceptance of such changes**.

**Contact Information**

If you have any questions or comments about this notice, the ways in which the Company collects and uses your information described herein, your choices and rights regarding such use, or wish to exercise your rights under California law, please do not hesitate to contact us at:

|     |     |
| --- | --- |
| Phone: | (800) 323-1229; Monday-Friday, 8:00 a.m. to 6:00 p.m. (U.S. Central Time) |
| Website: | [www.britannica.com](http://www.britannica.com/) |
| Email: | [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) |
| Postal Address: | Encyclopaedia Britannica, Inc.  <br>Attn: M.G. Kim, DPO  <br>325 N. LaSalle Street, Suite 200  <br>Chicago, Illinois 60654 |

**EU Data Subject Rights**
==========================

The EU GDPR and other countries’ privacy laws provide certain rights for data subjects. A good explanation of them (in English) is available on the website of the United Kingdom’s [Information Commissioner’s Office](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/data-protection-reform/overview-of-the-gdpr/individuals-rights/the-right-to-be-informed/).

If you wish to confirm that Encyclopaedia Britannica is processing your personal data, or to have access to the personal data Encyclopaedia Britannica may have about you, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

**EU Representative and Data Protection Officer**
=================================================

Encyclopaedia Britannica is headquartered in Illinois USA. Encyclopaedia Britannica has appointed an EU representative and data protection officer for you to contact if you have any questions or concerns about Encyclopaedia Britannica’s personal data policies or practices.

Our EU representative’s name and contact information are:

    Encyclopaedia Britannica EU Representative  
    Unity Wharf, 13 Mill Street  
    London SE1 2BH UNITED KINGDOM  
    [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Our data protection officer’s name and contact information are:

    M.G. Kim  
    Encyclopaedia Britannica Data Protection Officer  
    325 N. LaSalle Street, Suite 200  
    Chicago, IL USA 60654  
    [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

**Copyright**
=============

All of the content on the Services is copyrighted by Encyclopaedia Britannica, Incorporated, 354 N. LaSalle St., Suite 200, Chicago, Illinois 60654, or its licensors, and it cannot be redistributed or used for commercial purposes. More detailed information about Encyclopaedia Britannica’s copyrights and trademarks is available in our [Terms of Use](https://corporate.britannica.com/termsofuse.html).

**Business Transfers**
======================

As we continue to develop our business, we might sell or buy subsidiaries, or business units. In such transactions, customer information generally is one of the transferred business assets but remains subject to the promises made in any pre-existing Privacy Notice or Policy (unless, of course, the customer consents otherwise). Also, in the unlikely event that Encyclopaedia Britannica, or substantially all of its assets are acquired, customer information will be one of the transferred assets, and will remain subject to our Privacy Notice.

**Acceptance of Privacy Notice Terms and Conditions**
=====================================================

By using the Services, you signify your agreement to the terms and conditions of this Privacy Notice. If you do not agree to these terms, please do not use the Services. We reserve the right, at our sole discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions of this Privacy Notice at any time. If we make any material changes to this Privacy Notice that impact your privacy rights, we will notify you by posting a notice on the Services prior to the effective date of such changes with an opportunity for you to review the same, unless otherwise required by applicable law. All non-material amended terms automatically will take effect when they are posted on the Services. Please check this page periodically for any modifications. Your continued use of any of the Services following the posting of any non-material changes to these terms shall mean that you have accepted those changes. All other amended terms will take effect 30 days after you are notified of the same.

**Questions, Comments or Complaints**
=====================================

If you have questions about Encyclopaedia Britannica or its products, visit our [Contact Us](http://corporate.britannica.com/contact/) page to find email addresses and other contact information for the appropriate department. To correct, update, or remove personally identifiable information, please email us at [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection). If you have any questions or concerns, please send an email to [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or at [\[email protected\]](https://corporate.britannica.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

[

](https://corporate.britannica.com/)

Menu

[Privacy Policy](https://corporate.britannica.com/privacy-policy)      [Terms of Use](https://corporate.britannica.com/termsofuse.html)       Copyright 2024 Encyclopædia Britannica, Inc. Corporate Site. All rights reserved.
